Simeon BABATUNDE

423 Lindsay Road, Unit 509, Clemson, SC 29631, USA | <u>babatunde.simeon@gmail.com</u> | +1 (864) 650-2697 | http://simeonbabatunde.com

Career Summary

A second year PhD student in Computer Science with a background in embedded systems, software and data engineering. Interested in building tools and technologies that enable tiny batteryless sensors to power intelligent IoT. Working towards becoming a research leader in the emerging fields of AI and IoT.

Professional Experience

Graduate Research Assistant

Aug. 2017 - Present

PERSIST Research Lab, Clemson University, – Clemson, SC, USA.

- Researching efficient communication protocols for tiny batteryless sensors.
- Lead research works on networking for intermittently powered devices.

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Aug. 2017 – Present

School of Computing, Clemson University, - Clemson, SC, USA.

- Lead TA for CPSC 1071 (Programming Techniques and Methodology).
- Topics include structured programming, program design and implementation techniques, program testing and verification, basic data structures and analysis of algorithms using C and C++.
- Hold laboratory sessions, office hours, and coordinate other TA's in ensuring seamless content delivery.
- Lecture instructor: Catherine Hochrine.

Data Engineer

Dec. 2015 – Jul. 2017

Venture Garden Group, - Oregun, Lagos State, Nigeria.

- Developed and managed the first Enterprise Data Hub (EDH) built on Apache Hadoop ecosystem.
- Powered the data driven governance initiative in Nigeria through advanced and predictive analytics.
- Identified business problems to be solved with analytics and communicated findings to business decision makers.
- Won the first data science boot camp competition.

Software Developer & Data Analytics Researcher

Aug. 2014 – Nov. 2015

- Splashers Technologies Limited, Isheri North, Lagos State, Nigeria.
- Team Lead, Mobile Application Development. Won the Outstanding Contribution to Consolidation Goals Award, October 2015.
- Developed the first mobile solution for financial settlement among key stakeholders within the Nigerian power sector.
- Ensured new members of the mobile development team were trained and mentored on adoption and utilization of key technologies used by the team.

Academic Qualifications

• Doctor of Philosophy, Computer Science

2017 – 2022 (Anticipated)

Clemson University – Clemson, South Carolina, USA.

• Bachelor of Science, Computer Engineering Obafemi Awolowo University – Ile Ife, Osun State, Nigeria.

Sep. 2014

- ✓ First Class Honors, CGPA of 4.6 on a 5.0 scale.
- ✓ Second best graduating student in the department of Computer Engineering.

 National Diploma, Electrical and Electronics Engineering Federal Polytechnic Ilaro – Ogun State, Nigeria.

Distinction, 3.8 CGPA on a 4.0 scale. Graduated as the Best Engineering Student.

Selected Technical Skills

- **Programming Languages:** Proficient in C, Python, Java; comfortable with R, C++, Javascript, and SQL.
- Tools and Technologies: Autodesk Eagle, TI MSP430, Hadoop, ELK stack (ElasticSearch-Logstash-Kibana), Apache Spark, Sqoop, Hive, Pig, Kafka, Flume, Scikit-learn, Jupyter Notebook, StreamSets Data collector, Android, Nodejs, Django, Flask and LaTeX.
- Version Control Systems: Git, Subversion and Mercurial.
- Certifications: Data Science Specialization, Johns Hopkins University (Coursera).

Selected Projects

- UV Risk Detection and Prevention: A wearable device that informs the user about the current and cumulative UV rays exposure level (Github).
- **Private Object Detection in Images using YOLO:** A private and public object detection program built on yolov3 and darknet (Github).
- Packet Sniffing and Spoofing: A sniffer and spoofing program implemented using pcap library and raw socket in C (Github).
- Clemson Game day Queue Warning System: A customized queue warning system modeled using software verification and validation tools (AADL) and techniques (Github).
- Autonomous Line Following Robot: Built with the most basic electronic components (YouTube).

Extracurricular Experience

- Upsilon Pi Epsilon (CS Honor Society): Participated in the outreach program (robotics and coding camp) for elementary students at Forest Acres Elementary, Easley.
- Association for Computing Machinery (ACM): Student member.
- Engineers without Borders: Active member, Clemson chapter.
- School of Computing Graduate Students Association (Clemson): Active member.